So considerations for creating our project
charter.
Let's look at those EEFs again.
Remember those enterprise
environmental factors are things
beyond our control that will
impact us, impact our project.
They are external to the project.
The four main categories and those were
back on page 3840-ish in your Pimbach.
But the four main
categories for those enterprise
environmental factors
to help you remember.
Organizational culture, structure,
and governance.
Okay.
Remember, organizational
structure will determine whether
or not you have power and
authority on your projects.
Okay, so organizational culture,
structure, and governance.
And we have the project management
information system.
So they, I believe, have it noted as
information.
software or technologies
that we'll use, but most of the
time you will see project
management information system.
Any softwares, whether it's Microsoft
Project, Microsoft Office, Lotus Nodes,
Clarity, Timberline, Primavera,
whatever it is you're using, any
softwares, all your project information
will be coming in and out of there.
All right.
This will also be a tool and technique we
use.
We use the PMIS.
All right.
Organizations.
resources any people material equipment
supplies facilities already with the
organization these are EEFs we'll end up
using them as well all right then we have
government and industry standards laws
regulations we're going to have to follow
all right so um this will deal with
compliance as well now our OPAs
organizational process assets that's a way
to remember them so I want you to think
the PMO, PMO, is setting the policies,
processes, procedures, guidelines,
methods we're going to follow on our
projects.
All right, that's the first part of those
OPAs.
Then the second part will be the knowledge
repository, the best way
to think of this SharePoint.
All project information is compiled in
SharePoint that we can pull and use.
these are assets that we can use.
I want you to think configuration
management.
How we'll keep up and make sure we're
working from the latest plans,
versions, baselines, documents.
So think version control.
That's the biggest thing.
All right.
Historical information and lessons learned
huge.
History is bound to repeat itself if you
don't know what it was.
We document these things.
and we'll pull from them.
Look at what's happened before.
And with the lessons learned, we're going
to pull those as well.
What's gone well, what hasn't gone well on
previous projects.
And we'll also pull previous similar
recently completed project files.
Why would you reinvent the wheel if you do
the same types of projects over and over?
Look at them.
See what you can pull.
All right.
You don't just use.
a previous project files,
but see what is applicable
to your project, is what I was getting at.
All right, something else we consider when
we're developing the project charter,
assumptions and constraints.
So you will see that this is where we will
actually create as we develop the project
charter, our initial assumptions and
constraints log.
So I know it says
assumptions log, but I want
you to think assumptions
and constraints log.
So it's going to document any assumptions
we're making.
So assumptions are things we believe to be
true.
Like we'll use the same
contractors we use on the last project
or we assume certain
resources will be available to us.
So we document those things because we're
going to have to validate
those assumptions.
We also document constraints.
So a constraint is
anything that will impede
or dictate the actions
of the project team.
We have six constraints, and I believe
these are mentioned on another lesson,
but let's cover them again, just to make
sure we've got them.
So we have scope, time, and cost,
triple constraints.
I believe I actually discussed those in a
previous lesson.
But scope time and cost, those are triple
constraints or iron triangle.
But those are not the only constraints.
We also have quality.
resources are lack thereof and risks
uncertainties on our project these are all
constraints and often they are imposed on
us by our stakeholders especially schedule
and costs we need this work done in this
amount of time and this is the budget you
have to work with so we document all those
things document if you don't document
you're going to forget things all right
Other considerations.
Next slide.
We're going to gather data.
So we're trying to determine in our
project charter high level information,
like overall project objectives,
our high level requirements, summary
budgets, summary schedule, any
stakeholders that we know about,
key stakeholders we know about,
any risks we know about.
So ways of doing that, gathering the data,
brainstorming, usually a small group tries
to generate as many ideas about that
high-level information.
Focus groups, all right, we can get
pre-qualified SMEs together, and we can
interview any stakeholders we already know
about what are the high-level details.
And we'll use interpersonal and team
skills.
You'll see, we use these a lot.
anytime you're dealing with stakeholders,
including our team members.
We'll use those interpersonal team skills.
We're going to manage
conflict, facilitate meetings,
as well as manage meetings
as we have meetings.
So these interact with each other a lot.
So you'll see we'll use a lot of these
tools.
These are tools that we'll use.